A Guide to the Governor Mark R. Warner, Executive Office, Records, 2001-2006
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Mark R. Warner, Executive Office, Records 2001-2006
The Library of Virginia
42621, 42622, 42623, 42624, 42625, 42627
8.23 cu. ft. (24 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 42621-42625 and 42627 transferred on 7 April 2006.
Biographical Information
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor and Chief of Staff and their assistants. The Executive Office during Governor Mark R. Warner's administration (2002-2006) was responsible for the Governor's Weekly Status Reports, Cabinet Meeting Journals, and budget materials. On 10 December 2001, Governor-elect Warner, chose William H. Leighty, then director of the Virginia Retirement System, to serve as his Chief of Staff. In this position, Leighty duties included the administration of the state government planning budget process, administration of the state government personnel system, review (in the absence of the governor), major planning, budgetary, personnel, policy, and legislative matters, act as chief liaison officer with members of the General Assembly, and to act as Senior Executive Assistant (Warner Executive Order 3, 12 January 2002).
Scope and Content
The Governor Mark R. Warner, Executive Office, Records are housed in 24 boxes. The collection is arranged into four (4) series. Series have been designated for: I. Weekly Status Reports; II. Cabinet Meeting Journals; III. State Budget Files; and IV. Chief of Staff Files. These records include agreements, reports, correspondence, memorandums, budget documents, agendas, handouts, invitations, and speeches. This collection documents the issues and policy decisions of the Warner Administration (2002-2006) as well as the actions of Bill Leighty, Governor Warner's Chief of Staff.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Weekly Status Reports, 2002-2006
II. Cabinet Meeting Journals, 2002-2005
III. State Budget Files, 2004
IV. Chief of Staff Files, 2001-2006
Contents List
- I. Weekly Status Reports, 2002-2006 (accession 42624)., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 1-9)
  The Weekly Status Reports series is housed in 9 boxes, arranged chronologically and contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Governor's Cabinet, including the Secretaries of Administration (Sandra D. Bowen), Agriculture and Forestry (Robert S. Bloxom, 2004-2006), Commerce and Trade (Michael Schewel), Education (Belle S. Wheelan, 2002-2005 and Peter Blake, 2005-2006), Finance (John M. Bennett), Health and Human Resources (Jane H. Woods), Natural Resources (W. Tayloe Murphy, Jr.), Public Safety (John W. Marshall), Technology (George C. Newstrom, 2002-2004 and Eugene J. Huang, 2004-2006), and Transportation (Whitt Clement, 2002-2005 and Homer Pierce (2005-2006). Also included are reports by the Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (John Hager, 2002-2004 and George Foresman, 2004-2006) and the Office of Constituent Services (Rita R. Henderson, 2002-2004, Dietra Y. Trent, 2004-2005 and Margaret K. Hughson, 2005-2006). Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. The level of detail varied for each cabinet officer and items of importance were highlighted by staff for the Governor. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. Not all reports are extant and the first report does not begin until 21 March 2002. This series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Warner Administration.
  Notable topics and issues include: anti-gang initiative, avian flu outbreak in the Shenandoah Valley, Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission (BRAC), Budget Reduction Plans (2002), Capitol Square and Capitol Building renovations, Civil Rights Memorial, Drought (2002), Dulles Corridor Rail Project, 8th and 9th Street Office Buildings, Education for a Lifetime, eVa, Family Access to Medical Insurance Security (FAMIS), Higher Education Initiatives, Hurricane Isabel, I-81/PPTA, IT Transformation and creation of VITA, K-12 Initiatives, Library of Virginia maintenance issues, minority procurement and SWAM (Small, Women and Minority) business, Motorsports Initiative, Old City Hall in Richmond, Governor's Partnership for Achieving School Success (PASS), Race to GED, Tax Reform (2004), and Veterans Issues.
  - Reports prior to 21 March 2002 are not extant
  - 21 March 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 28 March 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reports for 4 April and 11 April 2002 are not extant
  - 18 April 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 25 April 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2 May 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 9 May 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 16 May, 23 May, 30 May and 6 June 2002 are not extant
  - 13 June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 20 June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 27 June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 11 July 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 18 July 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 25 July 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1 August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 8 August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 15 August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 22 August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 29 August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 6 September 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 13 September 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 20 September 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 27 September 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 4 October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 11 October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 18 October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 25 October 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1 November 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 8 November 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 15 November 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 22 November 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 29 November 2002 - no report
  - 6 December 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 13 December 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 20 December 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 27 December 2002 - no report
  - 3 January 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 10 January 2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 17 January 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 24 January 2003 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 31 January 2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 7 February 2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 14 February 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 21 February 2003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 28 February 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 7 March 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 14 March 2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 21 March 2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 28 March 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 4 April 2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 11 April 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 18 April 2003 - no report
  - 25 April 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 2 May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 9 May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 16 May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 23 May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 30 May 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 6 June 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 13 June 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 20 June 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 27 June 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 4 July 2003 - no report
  - 11 July 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 18 July 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 25 July 2003 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1 August 2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 8 August 2003 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 15 August 2003 - not extant
  - 22 August 2003 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 29 August 2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 5 September 2003 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 12 September 2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 19 September 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 26 September 2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 3 October 2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 10 October 2003 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 17 October 2003 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - 24 October 2003 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - 31 October 2003 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 7 November 2003 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 14 November 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 21 November 2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 28 November 2003 - no report
  - 5 December 2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 12 December 2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 19 December 2003 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 26 December 2003 - no report
  - 5 January 2004 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 16 January 2004 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 23 January 2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 30 January 2004 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 6 February 2004 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 13 February 2004 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 20 February 2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 27 February 2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 5 March 2004 to 9 April 2004 - not extant
  - 16 April 2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 23 April 2004 to 7 May 2004 - not extant
  - 14 May 2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 21 May 2004 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 28 May 2004 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 4 June 2004 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 11 June 2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 18 June 2004 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 25 June 2004 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 2 July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 9 July 2004 - no report
  - 16 July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 23 July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 30 July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 6 August 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 13 August 2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 20 August 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 27 August 2004 (2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 3 September 2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 10 September 2004 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 17 September 2004 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 24 September 2004 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1 October 2004 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 8 October 2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 15 October 2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 22 October 2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 29 October 2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 5 November 2004 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 12 November 2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 19 November 2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 26 November 2004 - no report
  - 3 December 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 10 December 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 17 December 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 24 December 2004 - no report
  - 31 December 2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 7 January 2005 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 14 January 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 21 January 2005 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 28 January 2005 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 4 February 2005 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 11 February 2005 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 18 February 2005 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 25 February 2005 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 4 March 2005 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 11 March 2005 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 18 March 2005 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 25 March 2005 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1 April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 8 April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 15 April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 22 April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - 29 April 2005 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - 6 May 2005 (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 13 May 2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 20 May 2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 27 May 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 3 June 2005 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 10 June 2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 17 June 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 24 June 2005 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1 July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 8 July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 15 July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 22 July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 29 July 2005 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 5 August 2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 12 August 2005 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 19 August 2005 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 26 August 2005 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 2 September 2005 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 9 September 2005 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 16 September 2005 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 23 September 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 30 September 2005 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 7 October 2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 14 October 2005 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 21 October 2005 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 28 October 2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 4 November 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 11 November 2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 18 November 2005 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 25 November 2005 - no report
  - 2 December 2005 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 9 December 2005 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 16 December 2005 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 23 December 2005 - no report
  - 30 December 2005 - no report
  - 6 January 2006 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 13 January 2006 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- II. Cabinet Meeting Journals, 2002-2005 (accession 42621)., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 10-13)
  The Cabinet Meeting Journals series is housed in 4 boxes and is arranged chronologically. The Cabinet Meeting Journals were maintained by Governor Warner's Chief of Staff, Bill Leighty and were kept in a binder by quarter. The Journals contain meeting agendas and presentation handouts of a variety of topics of current interest. Typically, the handouts included in the binder are from invited presenters to Cabinet meetings.
  Notable topics and items include: Drought Task Force Update (17 June 2002, 26 August 2002, 16 September 2002, 23 September 2002, 30 September 2002, 7 October 2002, 21 October 2002, 4 November 2002, and 2 December 2002); Implementing the Governor's Technology Strategic Plan (26 August 2002); King William Reservoir Briefing (23 September 2002); Preliminary Budget Outlook for the Rest of this Biennium (22 July 2002); Governor's Commission on Efficiency and Effectiveness, Working Report (16 December 2002); State of the Commonwealth Address, Draft, Version 3 (6 January 2003); SARS Update (28 April 2003); Preliminary Budget Outlook, 2004-2006 (16 June 2003); SWAM (25 July 2005); Chief Accomplishments List (19 September 2005 and 17 October 2005); Hurricane Katrina (19 September 2005).
  - January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - February 2002 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - March 2002 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - April 2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - May 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - June 2002 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - July 2002 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - August 2002 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - September 2002 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - October 2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - November 2002 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - December 2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - January 2003 - February 2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - March 2003 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - April 2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - May 2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - June 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - July 2003 - September 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - October 2003 - June 2004 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - July 2004 - September 2004 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - October 2004 - December 2004 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - January 2005 - April 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - May 2005 - June 2005 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - July 2005 - October 2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- III. State Budget Files, 2002-2004 (accessions 42622 and 42623)., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 14-20)
  The State Budget Files series is housed in 7 boxes and is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Impact of the Tax Reform Plan and the 2004-2006 Budget on Localities and Miscellaneous State Budget Files.
  - Impact of the Tax Reform Plan and the 2004-2006 Budget on Localities, 2004 (accession 42622).
    This subseries is housed in 6 boxes and is divided into two sections: alphabetical by member and alphabetical by locality. This is the larger of the two subseries and contains a comprehensive breakdown of the benefits of Governor Warner's 2004 Tax Reform Plan by House and Senate District and locality. Features include: changes in the standard deductions, rates and brackets, filing threshold and age deduction. Other features included an increase in the sales tax and state cigarette tax, and a reduction in the sales tax on food. The Locality breakdown includes a profile of residents and income tax returns for each locality in 2001.
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Bell through Chichester (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Colgan through Devolites (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Edwards through Hanger (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Hawkins through Lambert (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Locke through Lucas (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Marsh through Newman (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Norment through Potts (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Puckett through Quayle (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Rerras through Reynolds (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Ruff through Stosch (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Ticer through Watkins (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Member: Sen. Whipple through Williams (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Locality (County): Accomack County through Cumberland County (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Locality (County): Dickenson County through James City County (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Locality (County): King George County through Pulaski County (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Locality (County): Rappahannock County through York County (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Locality (City): Alexandria through Martinsville (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Locality (City): Newport News through Winchester (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Locality (Town): Abingdon through McKenney (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Locality (Town): Narrows through Wytheville (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Member: Book 4 containing information on districts of Delegates with surname beginning with A and part of B is missing (found see - Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Baskerville through Byron (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Callahan through Cosgrove (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Councill through Ebbin (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Eisenberg through Hargrove (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Hogan through Hurt (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Ingram through Jones (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Keister through Lewis (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Lingamfelter through May (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Member: Del. McDonnell through Moran (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Morgan through Parrish (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Peterson-Putney (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Rapp-Shannon (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Sherwood-Suit (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Tata-Ware (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Watts-Wright (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Organized by Member: Del. Abbitt-Barlow (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous State Budget Files, 2002-2004.
    This subseries is housed in one box and is arranged chronologically. The subseries contains budget documents but also several overviews of the Governor's emergency management responsibilities. Files include: Emergency/Disaster Responsibilities of the Governor of Virginia presented to Governor Mark R. Warner, January 2002; Public Safety Response to Terrorism, January 2002; One Virginia, One Future, Governor Warner's Economic Development Strategic Plan, Steering Committee Materials, Fall 2002; Draft - Report of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Biennial Report on the Economic Growth and Stability in Virginia's Urban Areas, 2002-2003; Department of Corrections Report of Findings Facility Condition Assessments 2003 Acts of Assembly, Item 408.D.1, 1 September 2003; Governor's Management Objectives, August 2004; and Jobs for Virginia, August 2004.
    - Emergency/Disaster Responsibilities of the Governor of Virginia presented to Governor Mark R. Warner, January 2002 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Public Safety Response to Terrorism, January 2002 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - One Virginia, One Future, Governor Warner's Economic Development Strategic Plan, Steering Committee Materials, Fall 2002 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Draft - Report of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Biennial Report on the Economic Growth and Stability in Virginia's Urban Areas, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Draft - Report of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Biennial Report on the Economic Growth and Stability in Virginia's Urban Areas, 2002-2003 (files copied from 3.5 inch disc) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Department of Corrections Report of Findings Facility Condition Assessments 2003 Acts of Assembly, Item 408.D.1, 1 September 2003 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Management Objectives, August 2004 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Jobs for Virginia, August 2004 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- IV. Chief of Staff Files, 2001-2006 (accessions 42625 and 42627)., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 21-24)
  Series consists of the general files of Bill Leighty, Chief of Staff for Governor Mark R. Warner. The files are divided into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Agency Executive Agreements and Correspondence. (4 boxes)
  - Agency Executive Agreements, 2002 (accession 42627).
    This subseries is housed in one box and is arranged alphabetically by cabinet secretary with state agencies filed therein. The Cabinet Secretary/Agency Head Executive Agreement was an agreement and partnership between Governor Mark R. Warner, cabinet secretaries and agency heads. It represented the commitment of agency leadership to assist the Governor in achieving his priorities and the Governor's commitment to support agency leadership in carrying out this agreement. Each agreement contains four parts: statement of purpose; a list of priorities, results, performance measures and action plan; statement of commitments; and signatures of agency head, cabinet secretary and Governor Warner. Nearly all of the agreements were signed in the summer of 2002.
    - Secretary of Administration and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Secretary of the Commonwealth (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Secretary of Education and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Secretary of Finance and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of Health and Human Resources and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Secretary of Public Safety and Agencies (part one) (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Secretary of Public Safety and Agencies (part two) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Secretary of Technology and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Secretary of Transportation and Agencies (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2001-2006 (accession 42625).
    This subseries is housed in three boxes. Correspondence (letters of recommendation, resignations, resignations, notes, thank you notes, invitations, and condolence letters) are arranged chronologically followed by miscellaneous materials and speeches. The Chief of Staff correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence, primarily to/from William H. Leighty. The majority of correspondence are requests for letters of recommendation, appointments and resignation. Notable letters include: Ray D. Pethel, appointed Interim Transportation Commissioner, 24 January 2002; Thomas J. Towberman, resignation as Commissioner of Virginia Employment Commission, 20 February 2002; Ron Angelone, not reappointed as Director, Department of Corrections, 28 August 2002; Jane N. Kusiak, resignation as Director of Policy, 13 September 2002; Cameron P. Quinn, not reappointed as Secretary, State Board of Elections, 13 January 2003; and Charles Macfarlane, resignation as Director, Department of Aviation, 2 June 2004.